Noor Ismot Ara

Portfolio: <u>BugHunterNoor.se</u> | LinkedIn: <u>Noor.Ismot</u> |

Github: Noor-Ismot

Email: ara.noor.ismot@gmail.com |

Mobile: 0767509527 |

Address: Stjärngatan 8A, 451 51 Uddevalla |



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Hi there! I'm Noor Ismot Ara, ISTOB certified and a dedicated Software Quality Assurance and Tester with 3.5 years of experience. I've worked on 20+ projects for a global pharmaceutical company, adhering to all test standards.

Skilled in creating <u>Manual</u> and <u>Automation testing</u>, <u>test plans</u>, <u>executing tests</u>, and <u>overseeing pre/post-release activities</u>. My <u>commitment</u> to excellence and <u>collaboration</u> with <u>diverse teams</u> ensures <u>meeting deadlines</u> and successful project delivery.

Currently working at **SustainLab**, integrating my software testing proficiency with **data analytics** technology. Outside of work, I enjoy listening to tech podcasts, <u>writing articles</u> on SQA, and traveling. I'm seeking to lead a challenging career and **contribute** to a **progressive company's goals** while **enhancing** my **skills and knowledge**.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SustainLab
Software Quality Assurance and Test Intern

Stockholm, Sweden
January 2024 - Present

Software Quality Assurance and Test Intern

- Performing all possible testing types on product
- Recording, reporting, and tracking defects throughout testing and managing them through JIRA
- Maintaining the bug life cycle
- Prepare documentation related to testing

Brain Station-23 Ltd

Dhaka, Bangladesh *July 2019 - November 2022*

SQA Engineer

- Conducted feature testing, sanity, regression, functional, UI and Automation testing for both web and mobile applications.
- Communicated and Collaborated with other teams (Developers, content factory, business, operation) to accomplish any project.
- Recording, reporting, and tracking defects throughout testing and managing them through JIRA
- Involved in Software Life Cycle (SLC) Documentation using Confluence
- Provided walkthroughs of the application to the client
- Provided support for post-release testing activities
- Led multiple projects with my teammates for test activities

Projects

- A Comprehensive Case study of a Tested global web application
- E-commerce Website Cypress Automation Test
- Programming Projects
- Mobile Application Test Case Sample

SKILLS & INTERESTS

- Web and Mobile application manual and **Automation testing with Cypress**
- JIRA, Trello, Confluence, GitHub
- Programming language: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python, SQL
- Ability to perform tasks efficiently within the deadline
- Familiarity with accessibility testing and security testing (with burp tool)

EDUCATION

East West University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Engineering

Dhaka, Bangladesh

2014 - 2018

Viqarunnisa Noon College Secondary & Higher Secondary Certificate (Science) Dhaka, Bangladesh 2001-2013

VOLUNTARY WORK

 General Committee Member at Youth School for Social Entrepreneurs (YSSE). (2019 January – 2019 May)

RESEARCH PAPERS

- Thesis on "Anomaly Based Intrusion Detection Using Dempster's Rule of Combination"
- Enthusiasm Against Cyber-Bullying: Intensity of Technical Knowledge and Analysis.
- Mining of Educational Dataset to Analyze Students' Academic Performance

URL: Research Papers

Languages:

Bengali (Mother language), English (Fluent), Urdu (Fluent), Hindi (Fluent), Swedish (Beginner)

Interests: Tech podcast, Nature Videography, Budgies, Traveling.